{"test_questions": [[{"question": "A micro array is an ordered array of microscopic elements on a planer substrate that allows the specific binding of", "opta": "gene or gene products", "optb": "whole genome", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Biochips are made up of", "opta": "semi-conducting molecules inserted into the protein frame work", "optb": "conducting molecules inserted into the protein frame work", "optc": "non-conducting molecules inserted into the protein frame work", "optd": "any of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Hypoxanthine can be measured by", "opta": "hypoxanthine sensor", "optb": "amorphous silicon ISFET", "optc": "urea sensor", "optd": "alcohol sensor", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following technology is used for micro array manufacturing?", "opta": "Photolithography", "optb": "Ink jetting", "optc": "Contact printing", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following adaptations would it be desirable for a farmer to breed into a crop of wheat?", "opta": "Early ripening", "optb": "Resistance to disease", "optc": "Resistance to pests", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the size (in kb) of the tobacco chloroplast genome?", "opta": "55 kilobase", "optb": "155 kilobase", "optc": "325 kilobase", "optd": "375 kilobase", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Gene banks conserve stocks of", "opta": "seed only", "optb": "vegetative material only", "optc": "seed and vegetative material both", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Microbiosensors are based on", "opta": "ions effect", "optb": "ionsensitive field effect transistor", "optc": "piezoelectric effect", "optd": "magnetic effect", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To qualify as a micro array the analytical device must be", "opta": "ordered", "optb": "microscopic", "optc": "planer and specific", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Microarrays are also known as", "opta": "biochips", "optb": "DNA chips", "optc": "gene chips", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pollination is the process by which plants transfer male sex cells from one plant to another. How does the nucleus of the male cell reach the female cell?", "opta": "It travels on the legs of bees and sticks to the egg cell", "optb": "The pollen grain grows a pollen tube and the nucleus travels down the pollen tube to reach the egg cell", "optc": "It blows in the wind", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a gardener takes a cutting from a plant, indicating that he has made a", "opta": "clone", "optb": "mutation", "optc": "new species", "optd": "new variety", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Single stranded circular RNA encapsidated with a larger RNA in a plant virus is", "opta": "a virion", "optb": "a viroid", "optc": "a virusoid", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Microarray analysis involves biological assays based on", "opta": "gels", "optb": "filters", "optc": "purification columns", "optd": "small glass chips", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is correct about micro biosensors?", "opta": "Implantation in human body and are suitable for in-vivo measurements", "optb": "Can be integrated on one chip and are useful for measuring various substrates in a small amount of sample solution simultaneously", "optc": "It is possible to develop disposable transducers for biosensors through mass production", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When farmers breed new plants they choose the pollen from one variety of plant and place it onto the stigma of another variety of plant. This type of plant breeding is known as", "opta": "selective breeding", "optb": "pollination", "optc": "seed collection", "optd": "cuttings", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The inosine and hypoxanthine can be determined simultaneously by using", "opta": "inosine sensor", "optb": "inosine and hypoxanthine sensor", "optc": "amorphous silicon ISFET", "optd": "urea sensor", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An ordered array is any collection of analytical elements configured in", "opta": "rows and columns", "optb": "randomly", "optc": "circle", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}